Guide to the Edgar Eugene Robinson Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
- Professional Correspondence Files, 1910-1952
  - (O - P), 1942-43 (Box 17, Folder 257)
    George W. Pierson, F. L. Paxson, Vera Pearson, Martin Polin.
  - (Pacific House), 1942-43 (Box 17, Folder 258)
    reports, Meetings, receptions.
  - (Q - R), 1942-43 (Box 17, Folder 259)
    Howard Quint (Especially re work in O. S. S. and Federal Communications Commission), W. T. Root, Letters re Alice Rose.
  - (Rugg Book Committee), 1942-43 (Box 17, Folder 260)
    Monroe E. Deutsch, reports, recommendations, Opinions, G. E. Hoover, J. L. Horn, L. D. Luckmann, H. R. McKinnon.
  - (Rugg Book Committee), 1942-43 (Box 17, Folder 261)
  - (S), 1942-43 (Box 17, Folder 262)
    Max Savelle, Charles C. Scott, Rixford K. Snyder, Marshall Stimson, Merrill Spalding, Earl Sohm, Howard M. Smyth.
  - (T - U), 1942-43 (Box 17, Folder 263)
    Donald Tresidder; Max Thelen; Comments on History Detp., Graduate Program, Organization, Etc. in letter to Tresidder, Elton Trueblood.
  - (V), 1942-43 (Box 17, Folder 264)
    N. Van Patten.
  - (W), 1942-43 (Box 18, Folder 265)
    Lynn White (oppinions on School of Humanities), R. L. Wilbur (Radio Program Unlimited Horizons), James T. Watkins, Oscar O. Winther, Attack on article The Hoover Frame of Mind by R. West appearing in Atlantis, Speaking Engagements, H. D. Winbigler, James P. Weter, Harry N. M. Winton, Edward White, W. reed West (re an Electons Yearbook), EER's gift of a Diary and an Exploration Journal to Library.
  - (XYZ), 1942-43 (Box 18, Folder 266)
    A. F. Simmerman
  - (A), 1943-44 (Box 18, Folder 267)
    Irwin Abrams, Herbert B. Alexander, Academic Council Minutes 1/14/44, R. F. Arragon.
  - (Army American History), 1943-44 (Box 18, Folder 268)
    Max Savelle, C. A. Barker, Administrative Problems, Examinations.
  - (B), 1943-44 (Box 18, Folder 269)
    Charles Barker, Gray C. Boyce, J. Earle Baker, Dana Barbour, Thomas A. Bailey, Frency relief Fund, William C. Bark, Speaking Engagements.
  - (C), 1943-44 (Box 18, Folder 270)
    Paul H. Clyde, Hardin Craig, Henry S. Commager, Harley Notter, Merle Curti, Commonwealth Club of California, Manoel Cardozo.
  - (D), 1943-44 (Box 18, Folder 271)
    Monroe E. Deutsch (Commonwealth Club), Philanthropy, John W. Dodds (Problems and Plans of School of Humanities and History Dept.), James C. DeVoss (Committee on the Teaching of American History in State Colleges), Paul H. Davis (Stanford Gift Activities), C. A. Dykstra.
  - (Departmental Program - Current), 1943-44 (Box 18, Folder 272)
    Max Savelle (History of Western Civilization),
  - (E), 1943-44 (Box 18, Folder 273)
    George F. Eliot.
  - (F), 1943-44 (Box 18, Folder 274)
    D. R. Fox, Benjamin Fine, Samuel T. Farquhar, G. S. Ford (American Historical review).
  - (G), 1943-44 (Box 18, Folder 275)
    Albert Guerard (work in New York), John Gange, Joseph F. Guffey, Cardinal Goodwin, mention of situation re Latin American Studies at Stanford, Robert R. Gros.
  - (H), 1943-44 (Box 18, Folder 276)
    David Harris, Dorothy H. Huggins, W. J. Hinton, Philip E. Mosely, Herbert Hoover.
  - (Hoover and Commonwealth Club), 1943-44 (Box 18, Folder 277)
  - (International Center), 1943-44 (Box 18, Folder 278)
    Minutes of Meetings of Board of Directors, E. Guy Talbott, Radio Program, Annual report of the San Francisco Committee on Foreign relations.
  - (J), 1943-44 (Box 18, Folder 279)
    W. T. Jackson, H. C. Jones (re Hichborn Materials).
  - (K), 1943-44 (Box 18, Folder 280)
    Louis K. Koontz, A. C. Krey, F. J. Klingberg.
  - (L), 1943-44 (Box 18, Folder 281)
    Thomas La Fargue, Ralph H. Lutz. (Los Angeles Conference on Post-War Education) Opinions, Speeches, Comments.
  - (M), 1943-44 (Box 18, Folder 282)
    H. F. McCreery, B. McAnear, Lloyd N. Morrisett (Conference on Planning Port-War Education), Max Savelle (re Henry Madden), Frederick Merk (Harvard Press Book Sale), H. Madden.
  - (N), 1943-44 (Box 18, Folder 283)
    Harley Notter, New York State Historical Association.
  - (P - Q), 1943-44 (Box 18, Folder 284)
    Langley Porter (Photostating the Wave) Howard Quint.
  - (R), 1943-44 (Box 19, Folder 285)
    J. S. Roucek, J. F. Rippy, Alice Rose.
  - (EER - Publications 1943-44) (Box 19, Folder 286)
    Conferences on History Teaching.
  - (replies from EER's PH.D.'s), 1943-44 (Box 19, Folder 287)
  - (S), 1943-44 (Box 19, Folder 288)
    R. K. Snyder, Max Savelle, Merrill Spalding, Engel Sluiter, Earl D. Sohm, Charles C. Scott.
  - (San Francisco Committee on Foreign relations), 1943-44 (Box 19, Folder 289)
    Council on World Affairs, Questionaire, reports on Meetings, Study Program.
  - (T), 1943-44 (Box 19, Folder 290)
    Donald B. Tresidder, W. W. Tinsley, Conference on Planning Post-War Education (Letter to D. B. Tresidder), Schools within University (Letter to D. B. Tresidder).
  - (U - V), 1943-44 (Box 19, Folder 291)
    Nathan Van Patten
  - (Universities' Committee on Post - War International Problems), 1943-44 (Box 19, Folder 292)
    Air Traffic, Colonies, Individual Freedoms, China.
  - (W), 1943-44 (Box 19, Folder 293)
    David E. Wynne, Hugo Wall, F. C. Wooton, J. P. Weter.
  - (War relocation Authority), 1943-44 (Box 19, Folder 294)
    Emery Fast
  - (XYZ), 1943-44 (Box 19, Folder 295)
  - (A), 1944-45 (Box 19, Folder 296)
    Irwin Abrams, Merle Alderman
  - (B), 1944-45 (Box 19, Folder 297)
    Arthur E. Bestor, Jr., Delmer M. Brown, T. A. Bailey, Charles A. Barker
  - (C), 1944-45 (Box 19, Folder 298)
    Hardin Craig, Paul H. Clyde, Manoel Cardozo.
  - (San Francisco Committee on Foreign relations), 1944-45 (Box 19, Folder 299)
    Proposed report of Committee for U. S. Nationalism, Commonwealth Club, International Center, Conference on Dumbarton Oaks Proposals, reports of Meetings, Membership List.
  - (Commonwealth Club Committee), 1942-45 (Box 19, Folder 300)
    Proposed research Project, Minutes of the research Advisory Council of the Commonwealth Club of California, Study Group on Legislature of California.
  - (D), 1944-45 (Box 19, Folder 301)
    Monroe E. Deutsch, Earl S. Douglass (President, Stanford Associates), Death of C. A. Duniway.
  - (E - F), 1944-45 (Box 19, Folder 302)
    Alvin C. Eurich (re Independent Study), English - Speaking Union, Temporary Council on Food for Europe's Children.
  - (G), 1944-45 (Box 19, Folder 303)
    L. M. Garrett, John Gange, Charles C. Scott, Palo Alto Historical records Committee.
  - (H), 1944-45 (Box 19, Folder 304)
    Max Thelen (re Charles E. Hughes and Election of 1916), Luella J. Hall, John Howell, David Harris,
  - (I), 1944-45 (Box 19, Folder 305)
    Yamato Ichihashi
  - (The Independent University and the Volunteer.), 1944-45 (Box 19, Folder 306)
  - (The Independent University and the Volunteer.), 1944-45 (Box 20, Folder 307)
  - (J - K), 1944-45 (Box 20, Folder 308)
    George Knoles, A. C. Krey, Louis K. Koontz.
  - (L), 1944-45 (Box 20, Folder 309)
    Thomas E. LaFargue, Walter Lippmann, R. H. Lowie.
  - (mc), 1944-45 (Box 20, Folder 310)
    Henry McCreery.
  - (M), 1944-45 (Box 20, Folder 311)
    Frederick Merk, Dudley T. Moorhead, Alexander Marchant, Anatole G. Mazour, Henry Madden.
  - (N), 1944-45 (Box 20, Folder 312)
    Harley Notter (Proposal for research in International relations), reinhold Niebuhr.
  - (New York Times), 1944-45 (Box 20, Folder 313)
    Institute of American History (teaching of American History), Benjamin Fine.
  - (O), 1944-45 (Box 20, Folder 314)
  - (P), 1944-45 (Box 20, Folder 315)
    Pacific House
  - (Q), 1944-45 (Box 20, Folder 316)
    Howard Quint
  - (R), 1944-45 (Box 20, Folder 317)
    Easton Rothwell, Alice Rose, J. Fred Rippy, W. T. Root, David Harris, H. E. rensch.
  - (E.E.R. Publications), 1944-45 (Box 20, Folder 318)
  - (S), 1944-45 (Box 20, Folder 319)
    Max Savelle (Including Plans for research) Rixford K. Snyder, Charles C. Scott.
  - (Social Studies School), 1944-45 (Box 20, Folder 320)
    E. A. Cottrell
  - (T), 1944-45 (Box 20, Folder 321)
    Max Thelen (copy of 1916 Letter to Travis H. Whitney), D. B. Tresidder, Payson J. Treat, R. G. Trotter.
  - (U - V), 1944-45 (Box 20, Folder 322-323)
    Nathan Van Patten, Vermont Historical Society.
  - (W), 1944-45 (Box 20, Folder 324)
    Oscar O. Winther, Dorothea Wyatt, (Manuscripts of Niebuhr Lectures), Lynn White, Evelyn Wrench Edward A. White, Donald B. Tresidder (Exhibition of Western Art), Rufus K. Wyllys, James P. Weter, O. H. Wedel, H. E. Westermeyer.
  - (Woodrow Wilson), 1944-45 (Box 20, Folder 325)
    T. A. Bailey ( Woodrow Wilson and the Great Betrayal)
  - (XYZ), 1944-45 (Box 20, Folder 326)
    Mary L. Ziebold, Arthur F. Zimmerman.
  - (A), 1945-46 (Box 20, Folder 327-328)
    Preston B. Albright, James G. Allen, Merle Alderman.
  - (American Council of Learned Societies), 1945-46 (Box 20, Folder 329)
  - (American Historical Association), 1945-46 (Box 20, Folder 330)
    Arthur P. Whitaker
  - (Atomic Age), 1945-46 (Box 20, Folder 331)
  - (B), 1945-46 (Box 20, Folder 332)
    Margery Bailey (Stanford Project on the Pioneer Culture of Early California), Muriel V. Sibell, C. F. Brand, Harold W. Bradley, Delmer Brown.
  - (C), 1945-46 (Box 20, Folder 333)
    Howard Clodius, California Advisors Committee
  - (Commonwealth Club: Pacific Ocean Problems Section), 1945-46 (Box 20, Folder 334)
    U. S. Policy in China, Minutes of Meetings.
  - (Commonwealth Club research Advisory), 1945-46 (Box 21, Folder 335)
    research Study of Population of California, Study of Propaganda, Minutes of Meetings, Constitution of research Service, Max Thelen.
  - (Committee on research: Commonwealth Club), 1945-46 (Box 21, Folder 336)
    American Council on Race relations, Monroe E. Deutsch, Davis McEntire, Minutes of Meetings, Max Thelen, Study of California Population Problems, Study of the Evacuation and resettlement of Japanese on the West Coast, Progress reports.
  - (Commonwealth Club research Advisory -- Population Study), 1944-46 (Box 21, Folder 337-337a)
    Minutes of Meetings, Memoranda, Monroe E. Deutsch, R. L. Wilbur, Rough Drafts, American Council on Race relations, Stuart R. Ward.
  - (D), 1945-46 (Box 21, Folder 338)
    Dwight L. Dumond, Monroe E. Deutsch, Thomas E. Drake, John P. Dern.
  - (E), 1945-46 (Box 21, Folder 339)
    Luther H. Evans, C. de Y. Elkus
  - (F), 1945-46 (Box 21, Folder 340)
    O. K. Flechtheim
  - (G), 1945-46 (Box 22, Folder 341)
    John Gange, A. Guerard
  - (H), 1945-46 (Box 22, Folder 342)
    David Harris, Federation of United Youth, John Howell (English - Speaking Union), Albert Hyma.
  - (Higher Education and National Affairs), 1945-46 (Box 22, Folder 343)
  - (International Center), 1945-46 (Box 22, Folder 344)
  - (J - K), 1945-46 (Box 22, Folder 345)
    John J. Johnson, George Knoles, (Save the Children Federation).
  - (L), 1945-46 (Box 22, Folder 346)
    Lloyd Luckmann, (International Center)
  - (Mc), 1945-46 (Box 22, Folder 347)
    Beverley McAnear, H. F. McCreery
  - (M), 1945-46 (Box 22, Folder 348)
    Frederick Merk, Dudley Moorhead, Henry Madden,
  - (N), 1945-46 (Box 22, Folder 349)
    Harley Notter, Alvin E. Nelson (Radio Station KNOX)
  - (A New American History), 1945-60 (Box 22, Folder 350)
    R. Lutz, J. E. W. Sterling, W. D. Wyman.
  - (The New United States), 1945-46 (Box 22, Folder 351)
    Elton Trueblood, O. H. Wedel, J. F. Rippy, F. L. Paxson, Waldo Chamberlin, Hardin Craig,
  - (The New United States), 1946 (Box 22, Folder 352)
    Publication Agreement, Business and Format Arrangements, Draft.
  - (O - P), 1945-46 (Box 22, Folder 353)
    Commonwealth Club Section on Pacific Ocean Problems.
  - (Institute of Pacific relations), 1945-46 (Box 22, Folder 354)
    Eugene Staley
  - (Q - R), 1945-46 (Box 22, Folder 355)
    Howard H. Quint, California Labor School, Alice Rose, William A. Robinson.
  - (Publications etc. E.E.R.), 1945-46 (Box 22, Folder 356)
    Twenty Years of Independent Study at Stanford University.
  - (S), 1945-46 (Box 22, Folder 357)
    Letters re Charles C. Scott, Max Savelle
  - (T), 1945-46 (Box 22, Folder 358)
    D. B. Tresidder (Problem of Overcrowding), Elton Trueblood, Informal Suggestions to Tresidder.
  - ( Twenty Years of Independent Study at Stanford University), 1945-46 (Box 22, Folder 359)
    O. H. Wedel, A. C. Krey, William Bary, John F. Gange, R. E. Swain.
  - (V - W), 1945-46 (Box 22, Folder 360)
    John Vandenburg, Dixon Wecter (Huntington Library) James T. Watkins, R. L. Wilbur, W. L. White (Campaign of 1912), Chester Rowell, World Student Service Fund, William Allen White Papers, R. L. Wilbur (U. N. Charter), J. P. Weter, World Book Encyclopedia, Woodrow Wilson Foundation.
  - (A), 1946-47 (Box 23, Folder 361)
  - (State requirement: American History), 1946-47 (Box 23, Folder 362)
    Lawrence A. Harper, Alvin C. Eurich.
  - (B), 1946-47 (Box 23, Folder 363)
    John D. Barnhart, Brookings Institution (Seminar on Problems of American Foreign Policy), William C. Bark (Hiring), Harold W. Bradley, Claude A. Buss, Arthur E. Bestor, Jr.
  - (C), 1946-47 (Box 23, Folder 364)
    Albert Coyle, Manoel Cardozo, Commonwealth Club
  - (Proposed Meeting: Committee on Fifty)., 1946 - 47 (Box 23, Folder 365)
  - (Commonwealth Club), 1946-47 (Box 23, Folder 366)
    Minutes of Meetings of Executive Committee and Board of Governors, Agenda, Treasurer's reports.
  - (D), 1946-47 (Box 23, Folder 367)
    Monroe E. Deutsch.
  - (E), 1946-47 (Box 23, Folder 368)
    A. C. Eurich, Luther Evans, English - Speaking Unions.
  - (F), 1946-47 (Box 23, Folder 369)
  - (G - H), 1946-47 (Box 23, Folder 370)
    John Gange, W. T. Hutchinson, Franklin Hichborn, Charles R. Hicks
  - (Stanford Conference on Humanities), 1946-47 (Box 23, Folder 371)
  - (I - K), 1946-47 (Box 23, Folder 372)
    Hiram W. Johnson, Jr., Paul Knaplund
  - (L - M), 1946-47 (Box 23, Folder 373)
    Death of E. G. Mears, Anatole G. Mazour (Appointment), Frederick Merk, Beverly McAnear.
  - (N - P), 1946-47 (Box 23, Folder 374)
    Alvin E. Nelson, Leo Pasvolsky (Brookings Institution), report of the Curriculum Committee for the School of Physical Sciences.
  - (R), 1945-47 (Box 23, Folder 375)
    Albert S. Rudda, Jr., Easton Rothwell
  - (E. E. R. Publications), 1946-47 (Box 23, Folder 376)
  - ( They Voted for Roosevelt) reviews, Thank-You Notes for Complementary Copies., 1946-47 (Box 23, Folder 377)
  - (S), 1946-47 (Box 23, Folder 378)
    Charles C. Scott, Merrill Spalding, J. E. W. Sterling.
  - (T), 1946-47 (Box 23, Folder 379)
    Max Thelen, H. F. Taggart, Donald B. Tresidder.
  - (U - V), 1946-47 (Box 23, Folder 380)
  - (W - Y), 1946-47 (Box 23, Folder 381)
    W. L. White, Arthur F. Wright (Stanford Appointment) Edward White, W. L. Westermann, George E. Worthington, John Watrous, Jr., Earl Warren.
  - (World Book Encyclopedia), 1946-47 (Box 23, Folder 382)
  - (A), 1947-48 (Box 24, Folder 383)
    Emergency Committee of Atomic Scientists, Irwin Abrans, Merle N. Alderman, American Council of Learned Societies ( Scholarship and Cataclysm: What is Happening to American History?)
  - (B), 1947-48 (Box 24, Folder 384)
    Harold W. Bradley, Arthur Bestor, Jr., C. A. Barker, A. Russell Buchanan, Thomas S. Barclay.
  - (C), 1947-48 (Box 24, Folder 385)
    Civil Rights reforms, How to Make Democracy Live, Meribeth Cameron, Paul H. Clyde, E. A. Cottrell, Gerald, Cullinan, J. E. W. Sterling, Waldo Chamberlin.
  - (Citizens' Committee for United Nations reform)., 1947-48 (Box 24, Folder 386)
  - (Commonwealth Club), 1947-48 (Box 24, Folder 387)
    Minutes of Meetings.
  - (Crary Project: The American Way of Life), 1947-48 (Box 24, Folder 388)
    Allan H. Crary
  - (D), 1947-48 (Box 24, Folder 389)
    Paul H. Davis, Monroe E. Deutsch (World Affairs Council of Northern California).
  - (E), 1947-48 (Box 24, Folder 390)
  - (F), 1947-48 (Box 24, Folder 391)
    H. H. Fisher (re John A. Hawgood, Bohvs Benes), Helen Fisher (research on Book About Leland Stanford), Freedom Train
  - (G), 1947-48 (Box 24, Folder 392)
  - (H), 1947-48 (Box 24, Folder 393)
    Franklin Hichborn (1910 Gubernatorial Campaign), Charles Hicks, C. H. Hunter, Edward M. Hulme.
  - (I), 1947-48 (Box 24, Folder 394)
  - ( Information Please Almanac - Role of Political Parties in American Public Life), 1947-48 (Box 24, Folder 395)
  - (Miss Cecilia Irvine), 1947-48 (Box 24, Folder 396)
  - (K), 1947-48 (Box 24, Folder 397)
    A. C. Krey, F. V. Keesling (including disposition of personal papers), F. J. Klingberg, Louis K. Koontz.
  - (L), 1947-48 (Box 24, Folder 398)
    T. R. Letts, R. D. Lapham, Henry R. Luce, R. M. Langdon.
  - (Mc), 1947-48 (Box 24, Folder 399)
    Beverly McAnear H. F. McCreery
  - (M), 1947-48 (Box 24, Folder 400)
    James C. Malin, Raymond Muse, Anatole G. Mazour, Dudley T. Moorhead, Malcolm Moule.
  - (Morrison Chair), 1947-48 (Box 24, Folder 401)
    Edgar E. Robinson Professorship, Edward Hohfeld, R. L. Wilbur.
  - (N), 1947-48 (Box 24, Folder 402)
    National Council Against Conscription, J. F. Neylan.
  - (O), 1947-48 (Box 24, Folder 403)
  - (P), 1947-48 (Box 24, Folder 404)
    Earl S. Pomeroy (re possible Biography of Hiram Johnson), R. R. Palmer (AHA Program).
  - (R), 1947-48 (Box 24, Folder 405)
    Nicholas Roosevelt, W. A. Robinson, Death of Chester H. Rowell (Including Correspondence with his daughter re Disposition of his Papers), Exchange of letters with nephew Billy [Robinson?]. A. Rodda, R. S. Rankin.
  - (E. E. R. Publications), 1947-48 (Box 24, Folder 406)
  - ( The Role of Political Parties in American Public Life), 1947-48 (Box 24, Folder 407)
  - (S), 1947-48 (Box 24, Folder 408)
    Charles C. Scott, Merrill Spalding, Harvey Wish.
  - ( Scholarship and Cataclysm), 1947-48 (Box 25, Folder 409)
    Manoel Cardozo, Robert E. Keohane, Edith Dobie, (Many Thank-You notes for complimentary copies in addition to those listed here).
  - ( Scholarship and Cataclysm: Correspondence), 1947-48 (Box 25, Folder 410)
    [Several Hundred Form Letters were discarded].
  - (T), 1947-48 (Box 25, Folder 411)
    Marco Thorne, Charles J. Tilly, Dorothy Thompson
  - (V), 1947-48 (Box 25, Folder 412)
    American Association for the United Nations, Inc.
  - (W-Y), 1947-48 (Box 25, Folder 413)
    Lynn T. White, O. H. Wedel, James P. Weter.
  - (Walgreen Foundation), 1947-48 (Box 25, Folder 414)
  - (A), 1948-49 (Box 25, Folder 415)
    Merle N. Alderman, Alert.
  - (B), 1948-49 (Box 25, Folder 416)
    C. A. Barker, J. Earl Baker (Situation in China) Harold W. Bradley, Claude A. Buss, Ray A. Billington, B. L. Borough, Theordore C. Blegen, Emma Beekman (History 2).
  - (C), 1948-49 (Box 25, Folder 417)
    Albert F. Coyle, Colonial Dames Essay Contest, Waldo Chamberlin, M. E. Cureton, Paul H. Clyde, Chaplain's Advisory Committee.
  - (Commonwealth Club), 1948-49 (Box 25, Folder 418)
  - (D - E), 1948-49 (Box 25, Folder 419)
    Marshall Dill, Jr., Edward Mead Earle, English -Speaking Union.
  - (F - G), 1948 - 49 (Box 25, Folder 420)
    Thomas H. Greer, Ralph H. Garriel.
  - Faculty Club, 1948-49 (Box 25, Folder 420a)
  - (A. A. Gray), 1948 - 49 (Box 25, Folder 421)
  - (H), 1948-49 (Box 25, Folder 422)
    W. B. Hesseltine, Huntington Library, Nation's Heritage.
  - (I), 1948-49 (Box 25, Folder 423)
  - (J - K), 1948-49 (Box 25, Folder 424)
    Hiram W. Johnson, Jr., P. C. Johnston, F. U. Keesling, George Knoles, A. C. Krey.
  - (L), 1948-49 (Box 25, Folder 425)
    John La Monte
  - (M), 1948-49 (Box 25, Folder 426)
    G. W. Meldrum, Raymond Muse
  - (N), 1948-49 (Box 25, Folder 427)
    Allan Nevins
  - (O), 1948-49 (Box 25, Folder 428)
  - (P), 1948-49 (Box 25, Folder 429)
    Langley Porter, Pacific Historical review, John Caughey, Harold W. Bradley
  - (Q - R), 1948-49 (Box 25, Folder 430)
    Howard Quint, Elmer E. Robinson, A. S. Rodda.
  - (E. E. R. Publications), 1948-49 (Box 25, Folder 431)
    Encyclopedia Britannica.
  - (S), 1948-49 (Box 25, Folder 432)
    R. G. Sproul, J. E. W. Sterling.
  - (Stanford University Press), 1948-49 (Box 25, Folder 433)
  - (T - U - V), 1948-49 (Box 25, Folder 434)
    John Vanderburg
  - (W - X - Y - Z), 1948-49 (Box 25, Folder 435)
    Edward A. White, Arthur P. Whitaker.
  - (A), 1949-50 (Box 26, Folder 436)
    Stanford Alumni Association
  - (B), 1949-50 (Box 26, Folder 437)
    B. L. Borough, Emma Beekman, Frances Barney, Arthur E. Bestor, Jr., H. W. Bradley.
  - (C), 1949-50 (Box 26, Folder 438)
    Howard Clodius, W. H. Cowley, Hardin Craig, Paul H. Clyde, John Caughey.
  - (D), 1949-50 (Box 26, Folder 439)
    Glenn S. Dumke, Alexander De Conde, D. Duggleby.
  - (E), 1949-50 (Box 26, Folder 440)
    Charles De Y. Elkus
  - (F), 1949-50 (Box 26, Folder 441)
    Benjamin Fine ( New York Times Survey on Education in History).
  - (G), 1949-50 (Box 26, Folder 442)
    A. A. Gray, A. Guerard, T. Gay, John Gange, G. Fores - Ganzon.
  - (H), 1949-50 (Box 26, Folder 443)
    Clarence Henkel, Charles W. Hackett.
  - (I), 1949-50 (Box 26, Folder 444)
    Cecilia Irvine, Alice Ingram.
  - (J), 1949-50 (Box 26, Folder 445)
    Hiram W. Johnson Jr., International Christian University in Japan.
  - (K), 1949-50 (Box 26, Folder 446)
    A. C. Krey, Edward C. Kirkland.
  - (L), 1949-50 (Box 26, Folder 447)
    Henry C. Luckey
  - (M), 1949-50 (Box 26, Folder 448)
    Henry McCreery, Dumas Malone, M. Moremen, Frederick Merk.
  - (N), 1949-50 (Box 26, Folder 449)
    reinhold Niebuhr, Allan Nevins (including oral History Project) Harley Notter.
  - (O - P), 1949-50 (Box 26, Folder 450)
    Dayton Phillips
  - (The Political Significance of the U.S.), 1949-50 (Box 26, Folder 451)
  - (R), 1949-50 (Box 26, Folder 452)
    Geroid T. Robinson, Elmer E. Robinson, Albert Rodda.
  - (E. E. R. Publications), 1949-50 (Box 26, Folder 453)
    Encyclopedia Britannica, AHA, Calif. Historical Society.
  - (S), 1949-50 (Box 26, Folder 454)
    N. Van Patten (re Elmer E. Robinson Materials), Address by R. G. Sproul, Life Magazine, Charles C. Scott, Max Savelle, William R. Steckel.
  - (T), 1949-50 (Box 26, Folder 455)
    Y. Takagi.
  - (V - W - Y), 1949-50 (Box 26, Folder 456)
    J. P. Weter, Death of R. L. Wilbur, O. O. Winther
  - (A), 1950-51 (Box 26, Folder 457)
    American Association of University Professors, Merle N. Alderman,
  - (American History requirement), 1950-51 (Box 26, Folder 457A)
  - (The Abuse of Freedom), 1950-51 (Box 26, Folder 457B)
  - (B), 1950-51 (Box 26, Folder 458)
    A. Russell Buchanan, H. W. Bradley, B. L. Borough.
  - (C), 1950-51 (Box 26, Folder 459)
    Hardin Craig
  - (D), 1950-51 (Box 26, Folder 460)
    Alexander DeConde, D. R. Duggleby
  - (E), 1950-51 (Box 26, Folder 461)
    Location of Robert E. Peary Papers, Charles De Y. Elkus Edward M. Earle
  - (Educational Testing Service), 1950-51 (Box 26, Folder 462)
  - ( Encyclopedia Britannica - revisions), 1950-51 (Box 27, Folder 463)
  - (F), 1950-51 (Box 27, Folder 464)
    Freedoms Foundation
  - (G), 1950-51 (Box 27, Folder 465)
    John Gange, A. A. Gray.
  - (H), 1950-51 (Box 27, Folder 466)
    Interim report on German Foreign Service Trainees Program, E. A. Hornig, Clarence renkel.
  - (I - J - K), 1950-51 (Box 27, Folder 467)
    A. C. Krey, F. V. Keesling (Stanford's Acquisition of his papers).
  - (L), 1950-51 (Box 27, Folder 468)
  - (M - N), 1950-51 (Box 27, Folder 469)
    Donald C. McKay, J. F. Neylan, Allan Nevins.
  - 1950-51 (Box 27, Folder 470)
  - ( Presidential Vote 1948 - correspondence), 1950-51 (Box 27, Folder 471)
    D. B. Truman
  - (R), 1950-51 (Box 27, Folder 472)
    Easton Rothwell, A. Rodda, J. William Robinson, Thoreau Raymond.
  - (E. E. R. Addresses), 1950-51 (Box 27, Folder 473)
    History in the Making,
  - (E. E. R. Publications), 1950-51 (Box 27, Folder 474)
  - (S), 1950-51 (Box 27, Folder 475)
    W. R. Steckel
  - (T), 1950-51 (Box 27, Folder 476)
    Arnold J. Toynbee, Clarence Thurber